<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>literature on Rishabh's Blog</title><link>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/tags/literature/</link><description>Recent content in literature on Rishabh's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 22:29:32 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/tags/literature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Walk Between PG and Office</title><link>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/walk_between_pg_and_office/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 22:29:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/walk_between_pg_and_office/</guid><description>This is the story of what goes on in my mind while I&amp;rsquo;m walking from pg to office or office to pg.
First thing I wanna mention is Ashirwad it&amp;rsquo;s a house near our office which has a circular tower rising on top of it&amp;rsquo;s roof which makes it look like a fort it has a big garden I don&amp;rsquo;t like it much but that circular tower grabs my attentioin every morning I pass by it.</description></item><item><title>Division by zero</title><link>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/division_by_zero/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 21:51:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/division_by_zero/</guid><description>A human story about science.
Division by zero is a short story by Ted Chiang.
It&amp;rsquo;s a story about a mathematician proving arithmatic is incosistent. That two is equal to one without using division by zero.
The proof is not important but it&amp;rsquo;s implication is not on the world but on the mathematician who proved it. I never imagined that if somebody wrote a story about arithmatic being incosistent it would focus on the mental health of the individual who proved it.</description></item><item><title>Towers of Babylon</title><link>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/towers_of_babylon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 20:38:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/towers_of_babylon/</guid><description>A beautiful story with and unexpected ending. Towers of babylon is a short story by Ted Chiang.
It introduced me to towers of babylon. The story follows Hellalium who&amp;rsquo;s a miner from elam. Who&amp;rsquo;s questions about the tower reflect some of mine. Including why is there even a tower, is it morally right for humans to open the vaults of heaven. What about the humans who live on the tower. Who have never what land looks like whose plants grow downward rather than upward for them sun never reaches a place higher than themselves.</description></item></channel></rss>