<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kafka on Rishabh's Blog</title><link>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/tags/kafka/</link><description>Recent content in Kafka on Rishabh's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 11:32:20 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/tags/kafka/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kafka With Spring</title><link>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/kafka_with_spring/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 11:32:20 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/kafka_with_spring/</guid><description>In the last blog we learned how to implement kafka consumer-publisher using plain kotlin. In this blog we&amp;rsquo;ll walk through some code to implement the same using Spring.
Spring makes the implementation rather simple. We need to create a configuration class and then we can add all our code there.
Setting up the configuration class We need two annotations for this Configuration and EnableKafka. We can also take some time to pick the value for bootstrapAddress and topic name from application.</description></item><item><title>Kafka With Kotlin</title><link>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/kafka_with_kotlin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 13:02:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/kafka_with_kotlin/</guid><description>In this blog we&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to interact with a kafka broker using plain kotlin.
Generating a kafka project. For this we&amp;rsquo;re going to generate a spring project using spring initializer. Select the dependency Spring for Apache Kafka. We are adding this dependency so later on we can start using spring for our kafka interactions.
Spinning up kafka and zookeeper. Once you&amp;rsquo;ve generated your project you&amp;rsquo;ll need to spin up an instance of kafka and zookeeper.</description></item><item><title>Basics of Kafka</title><link>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/basics_of_kafka/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 12:38:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/basics_of_kafka/</guid><description>Kafka is a distributed event logging system. It&amp;rsquo;s widely used in event event driven system as framework of choice.
Events We learned about these the last time in Event Driven Systems. In kafka an event is represented by a key-value pair. A key can be null as well. Topics A topic is an ordered log A new event is appended to end of a topic. A topic is not a queue it&amp;rsquo;s a proper Log.</description></item></channel></rss>