<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Rishabh's Blog</title><link>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Rishabh's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 22:29:32 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Walk Between PG and Office</title><link>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/walk_between_pg_and_office/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 22:29:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/walk_between_pg_and_office/</guid><description>This is the story of what goes on in my mind while I&amp;rsquo;m walking from pg to home or home to pg.
First thing I wanna mention is Ashirwad it&amp;rsquo;s a house near our office which has a circular tower rising on top of it&amp;rsquo;s roof which makes it look like a fort it has a big garden I don&amp;rsquo;t like it much but that circular tower grabs my attentioin every morning I pass by it.</description></item><item><title>Division by zero</title><link>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/division_by_zero/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 21:51:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/division_by_zero/</guid><description>A human story about science.
Division by zero is a short story by Ted Chiang.
It&amp;rsquo;s a story about a mathematician proving arithmatic is incosistent. That two is equal to one without using division by zero.
The proof is not important but it&amp;rsquo;s implication is not on the world but on the mathematician who proved it. I never imagined that if somebody wrote a story about arithmatic being incosistent it would focus on the mental health of the individual who proved it.</description></item><item><title>Maharaja trophy final</title><link>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/maharaja_trophy_final/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 18:18:48 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/maharaja_trophy_final/</guid><description>Exciting match at chinnaswamy stadium. It was friday 26th August 2022 when I went to see the final match of maharaja trophy played between banglore and gulbarga.
I went to the final with few of my friends and it was a lot of fun and the match was worth the money which was not much one ticket costed us around Rs. 110 but the match we saw had us on the edge of our seats the entire team both teams scored more than 200 runs and it was a sight to see.</description></item><item><title>Hosting Hugo on GitHub</title><link>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/hosting_hugo_on_github/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 14:10:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/hosting_hugo_on_github/</guid><description>Hosting your static site on Git Hub. This post assumes that you followed this tutorial to create your hugo static site on local machine.
Create a repo on GitHub To host your site on github you need to create your repo with a particular name
&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;.github.io You should push your repo here.
Add this file to automate github actions name: github pages on: push: branches: - main # Set a branch to deploy pull_request: jobs: deploy: runs-on: ubuntu-20.</description></item><item><title>Hugo</title><link>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/hugo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 09:07:48 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/hugo/</guid><description>Hugo Hugo is a static site creator which allows you to write md files and converts them to beautiful html pages.
This tutorial is about developing a static site server on you local machine. We will see how you can install hugo in you machine we will create a site, we will add a theme and we will add a post to that site.
Installation Hugo is very easy to install and start working with it will get you writing really quickly.</description></item><item><title>Static Methods</title><link>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/static_methods/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 08:27:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/static_methods/</guid><description>Static Methods in JavaScript To understand static methods first we need to know what are normal methods of a class.
Normal Methods All methods are defined and their reference is stored only once inside a class.
So how do all instances of class have access to that method?
What happens is that each instance first looks for which class it belongs to then it goes and looks for the method reference that was called upon and then we can think that the instance is sent as the first argument to that method but in reality it is bound to that method so nobody needs to send it as an argument.</description></item><item><title>Towers of Babylon</title><link>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/towers_of_babylon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 20:38:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://sharma-rishabh.github.io/posts/towers_of_babylon/</guid><description>A beautiful story with and unexpected ending. Towers of babylon is a short story by Ted Chiang.
It introduced me to towers of babylon. The story follows Hellalium who&amp;rsquo;s a miner from elam. Who&amp;rsquo;s questions about the tower reflect some of mine. Including why is there even a tower, is it morally right for humans to open the vaults of heaven. What about the humans who live on the tower. Who have never what land looks like whose plants grow downward rather than upward for them sun never reaches a place higher than themselves.</description></item></channel></rss>